<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - Alex Carrillo - Heart and Soul</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | Alex Carrillo - Heart and Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 19:33:27 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Collaboration Isn&#39;t a Checkbox</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/collaborationcheck/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 19:33:27 -0600</pubDate>
    <author>Alex Carrillo</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/collaborationcheck/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/blog/valorant.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>When “leadership” means control, and “collaboration” is just a fancy way to say: “Here’s what we’ve already decided, you’re just here so it looks like you were involved.”</p>
<p>And I get it. I’ve done it too. 🙋‍♂️</p>
<p>There’s this subtle thing that happens in some teams. You walk into a meeting, maybe a sprint planning, maybe a refinement, and there is something already prepared. The architecture is drawn. The decisions are made. But the team is asked for “input.”</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>From an Eye Exam to a WhatsApp Bot</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/whatsappbot/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 19:33:27 -0600</pubDate>
    <author>Alex Carrillo</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/whatsappbot/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/blog/whatsappbot.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Last week, I went to the ophthalmologist to get my vision checked. You know, just the usual: reading tiny letters on a chart, and the doctor asking if &ldquo;this one or that one&rdquo; looks clearer.</p>
<p>As he was examining my eyes, we started chatting. At one point, he asked what I do for a living. I mentioned I work in software development, and suddenly he seemed more curious, kind of like when someone realizes you might be able to fix that annoying tech problem they’ve been silently suffering with.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Vanity Metrics: The KDA of Developers</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/vanitymetrics/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 19:33:27 -0600</pubDate>
    <author>Alex Carrillo</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/vanitymetrics/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/blog/valorant.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Someone asked me:<br>
<em>&ldquo;Hey, can you accept my pull request? And if possible… could you travel back in time so the average resolution time doesn’t go up?&rdquo;</em> I laughed. But deep down, I knew I’d heard versions of that line <em>way</em> too many times lately.</p>
<p>Somewhere along the way, we confused <strong>metrics</strong> with <strong>meaning</strong>. There’s this phrase floating around in the IT world: <em>“You can’t improve what you can’t measure.”</em> And sure, it has its place. It helps us stay grounded, know where we are, and track progress. But I’ve been thinking more about Aristotle lately, specifically his idea of virtue being the balance between extremes. Not too little, not too much. Just right. (Thanks Mateus, <a href="https://mindshop.cafe/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Mindshop</a> really helps). 💡</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Zombies of Value: How Good Intentions Kills Ownership</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/zombiesofvalue/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 19:33:27 -0600</pubDate>
    <author>Alex Carrillo</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/zombiesofvalue/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/blog/zombievalue.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>The other day, I was chatting with a friend who’s a Product Manager, and she recommended me the book “What Got You Here Won’t Get You There” by Marshall Goldsmith, and one idea that really stuck with me was the concept of “Adding Too Much Value.” It hit close to home because I’ve been there, and that idea has seriously shaped the way I work on a team.</p>
<p>When I was a junior engineer, I struggled with ownership. Even if I was technically assigned to a task, it rarely felt like it was mine. <strong>Any idea I had would usually get polished or replaced before it could take real form.</strong> The intention behind that feedback was good, to deliver the best possible result ✨, but the side effect? I never really built confidence in my own voice or felt the full weight of responsibility.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Yes, it is possible</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/yesitispossible/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 19:33:27 -0600</pubDate>
    <author>Alex Carrillo</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/yesitispossible/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/blog/yesno.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Throughout my career as a Software Engineer, I’ve had the chance to face a wide range of software errors, from isolated cases to full system failures.
It’s fascinating to observe how different people take different paths to reach the same destination: the root cause. But I want to talk about a behavior that, unfortunately, I see repeating itself over and over again when trying to find &ldquo;the needle in the haystack.&rdquo;</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
